

# 13395 Village Park Dr. B6, Southgate 48195 maryjatkow@gmail.com 269.339.1782

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Nonprofit program coordinator and Library & Information Science graduate student with over 5 years of experience in curating digital collections; creating educational resources; coordinating and facilitating programs; and optimizing communication and organizational strategies to improve accessibility of education.

- Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Dream Suite, CRM Systems, Google Apps,
- Digital Curation & Research
- Teaching & Presenting

- Project Management
- Media Design & Publicity
- Program & Event Coordinating
- Organized & Goal-Oriented

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Learning & Engagement Programs Coordinator**

AUG 2017 - PRESENT

THE HENRY FORD - 20900 OAKWOOD BLVD, DEARBORN, MI 48124

- Developed interdisciplinary learning resources by writing facilitation guides & curating museum content
- Designed verbal content for Model I learning framework & educational resources
- Managed program & network development of statewide student invention competition
- Facilitated professional development on Innovation Education for educators
- Promoted & maintained teacher partnerships and network through online and onsite outreach

### National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Project Coordinator

Nov 2016 - Aug 2017

THE HENRY FORD - 20900 OAKWOOD BLVD, DEARBORN, MI 48124

- Organized NEH workshop in collaboration with university scholars and curators
- Managed grant budget and assisted with reports & applications
- Recruited over 200 workshop applicants by promoting workshop through various media channels
- Managed workshop communication, contracts, stipends, and materials for the 70 participants

Substitute Teacher Aug 2016 – Feb 2017

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATIONAL STAFFING GROUP, LLC

- Fulfilled long term substitute position for Special Ed & ASD classrooms in Washtenaw County
- · Taught high school and middle school math, history, ELA, Spanish, and Art in Wayne County

# Docent Staff(Supervisor)

**SEPT 2013- APRIL 2016** 

University of Michigan Museum of Natural History – 1109 Geddes Ave, Ann Arbor, MI

- Supervised museum and 5+ docents on weekends and events
- Led natural science and prehistoric school programs and public tours
- Designed materials, crafts, and activities for educational programs & events
- Assisted in the development of programs such as My Turn Program (Sensory Friendly Event), Discovery Days, summer camp, and scout programs

#### **Education and Visitors Program Intern**

May 2015-Aug 2015

MONTICELLO, THOMAS JEFFERSON FOUNDATION - CHARLOTTESVILLE, VA

- Presented over 100 tours about Thomas Jefferson, the plantation and the lives of the enslaved
- Recruited volunteers through social media, online advertisement, flyers, and open house

## **EDUCATION**

#### MLIS, Wayne State University

Aug 2018 -

Library and Information Science, Certification in Archival Administration

BA, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

SEPT 2012 - APRIL 2016

History with minors in Museum Studies and Anthropological Archaeology